<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Gadget on y15a</title><link>https://www.y15a.com/en/tags/gadget/</link><description>Recent content in Gadget on y15a</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.134.3</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 12:03:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.y15a.com/en/tags/gadget/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Essential apps on my Mac: 2024</title><link>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/essential-apps-on-my-mac-2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 12:03:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/essential-apps-on-my-mac-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>I rely on my MacBook Pro for both life and work. As such, I have a wide range of apps installed for business administration, software development, design, photography, and everything in between. Here’s a list of the apps I use heavily, regardless of the project I’m working on at the moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="alfred-5">Alfred 5&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.alfredapp.com/">Alfred 5&lt;/a> is a powerful Spotlight replacement for Mac. It offers file search, shortcuts, dictionary, and recently, AI integration. The best thing about Alfred is its customisability. Some of the workflows I use the most are:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About that iPhone announcement</title><link>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/iphone-15/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 08:23:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/iphone-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>USB-C. It&amp;rsquo;s about time, but for models with A16, it&amp;rsquo;s still running USB 2.0. Probably due to the lack of USB 3.0 controller in the chipset. Not that anyone would be troubled by the sub-GB/s bandwidth in this wireless age, but for an industry flagship product to have technology THIS old is kind of comical.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the weaker Yen, the new iPhone 15 Pro base model costs about the same as a month&amp;rsquo;s rent for my house. It accommodates a family of four, and a dog, comes with a parking space, located in a town that&amp;rsquo;s 30 minutes away from Tokyo by train.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MacBook Pro 14-inch, 2nd gen</title><link>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/mbp14-2gen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 05:17:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/mbp14-2gen/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been with it for over a month now. This is easily the best computer I&amp;rsquo;ve ever owned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t have to go over the performance and battery life offered by Apple Silicon, as its superiority is apparent in spec sheets and rave reviews. Still, this thing handles pretty much everything I throw at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a technical startup CEO, I split my time between People, Capital, Product and Administration. MacBook Pro will keep up with it for an entire day. Video conferencing for hours? No problem. Opening a large spreadsheet for financial modelling? Easy. Running virtualised Linux servers through Docker for Mac? It&amp;rsquo;s faster than running it bare metal on an Intel laptop.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>