<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Software on y15a</title><link>https://www.y15a.com/en/tags/software/</link><description>Recent content in Software on y15a</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.134.3</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 12:03:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.y15a.com/en/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Essential apps on my Mac: 2024</title><link>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/essential-apps-on-my-mac-2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 12:03:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/essential-apps-on-my-mac-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>I rely on my MacBook Pro for both life and work. As such, I have a wide range of apps installed for business administration, software development, design, photography, and everything in between. Here’s a list of the apps I use heavily, regardless of the project I’m working on at the moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="alfred-5">Alfred 5&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.alfredapp.com/">Alfred 5&lt;/a> is a powerful Spotlight replacement for Mac. It offers file search, shortcuts, dictionary, and recently, AI integration. The best thing about Alfred is its customisability. Some of the workflows I use the most are:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My first 50 days of being the lead software engineer (again)</title><link>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/first-50-days-of-being-a-lead-again/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 06:56:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/first-50-days-of-being-a-lead-again/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recent departures at our company led to a lack of technical leadership, especially in the infra/backend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had two choices. One is to scramble to hire a tech lead. Two is for me to assume the role temporarily while simultaneously functioning as the CEO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We went for the second option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may seem like a red flag to some people. It is not ideal. Equally, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready to throw someone into a job where they faced technical obstacles while understanding the users, the team, and the codebase. I was not confident enough to complete the hire in a month.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DjangoCongress JP 2018</title><link>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/talk-at-djangocongress/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/talk-at-djangocongress/</guid><description>&lt;p>I gave a talk at &lt;a href="https://djangocongress.jp/2018">DjangoCongress JP 2018&lt;/a> named &amp;ldquo;Django in the age of AI - the Good, the Bad and the Ugly&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been somewhat distant from the local Python community since I helped run PyCon JP 2014 as a publicity team member. I hope my talk was interesting enough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>JAWS DAYS 2018</title><link>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/jaws-days-2018/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.y15a.com/en/posts/jaws-days-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://ascii.jp/elem/000/001/673/1673409/">AI英会話アプリ「TerraTalk」のHeroku＋AWS活用法&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I gave a talk at an AWS user conference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spoke about the technical challenges of &lt;a href="https://www.terratalk.rocks/">AI English learning app TerraTalk&lt;/a>, the back-end configuration and our agility-first architecture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thank you to everyone involved for the opportunity!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>